# **ARTEM KOSTIUK**

Back-end/Software developer

Bila Tserkva, Ukraine kostiuk.ao@gmail.com +380936111446 linkedin.com/in/postatum

#### **SUMMARY**

Having 9 years of web and software development experience, took lead in software development, testing and debugging. Reduced e-commerce app memory usage by 80%. Mentored and supervised a team of developers. Utilized a number of programming languages to implement concepts in different areas. Supportive team member, passionate problem solver and environmental enthusiast.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Software developer | Ramses Tech Inc. | Remote | February 2015 - Present

- Developed Ramses API Framework (github.com/ramses-tech/ramses) using Python, which attracted the attention of 300+ developers.
- Improved code matching accuracy from 50% to 90% by tweaking Tree Edit Distance algorithm and search engine configuration.
- Maintained a dozen open-source libraries written in JavaScript, Scala, Python, Java.
- Developed refactoring tools utilizing Machine Learning, code parsing and generation.

Back-end developer | SteelKiwi Development | Remote | July 2014 - February 2015

- Developed web apps with Python, Django, JavaScript, SOLR.
- Developed and maintained web scrapers and automation bots using Selenium and Scrapy.

Web developer | 42 Coffee Cups | Remote | February 2013 - June 2014

- ullet Developed web apps with Python, Django, JavaScript, HTML, CSS along with  $\sim \! 10$  web scrapers.
- Reduced e-commerce app memory usage by 80% by finding and fixing a memory leak.
- Mentored and supervised a team of developers.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Master of Business Administration and Management**

Interregional Academy of Personnel Management, Kyiv, Ukraine Graduated 2010

#### **TRAINING**

AWS Developer Series XSeries (edX, 2020), Parsing Algorithms (Udemy, 2020), MongoDB for Developers (10gen, M101P, 2013), Introduction to Computer Science and Programming (edX, MITx 6.00x, 2012), Web Application Engineering (Udacity, CS253, 2012).